BAYU BAGUS BAGASWARA

bayubagusbagaswara@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/bayubagusbagaswara | +6282211211209

Objective

I am passionate about software development which includes backend engineering, API architecture, and web programming. Has work experience in the field technology research, banking industry, and the mining companies. Experience in building web applications and APIs for mobile applications.

Experience

PT Bank Danamon Indonesia / member of MUFG as a global financial group *Java Developer*

Jakarta, Indonesia Dec 2023 – present

- Joined the IT Trade Finance and Custody
- Developing a Custody Support Application (CSA) website applications to support all custody transaction activities carried out by Custody Users.
- Developing a REST API for the Billing feature with 3 customer categories including Core, Fund, and Retail customers. Use Thymeleaf to create PDF billing templates.
- Tech Stack: Java 8, Spring Boot, Thymeleaf, SQL Server.

PT Bank Syariah Indonesia / Biggest sharia banking in Indonesia *Back End Developer*

Jakarta, Indonesia

Feb 2023 - Dec 2023

- Developing Super App mobile banking Bank Syariah Indonesia, fixing bugs, refactoring existing code, and collaboration with the Agile Investment and Savings team to develop Investment and Savings products.
- Developing REST API features for Mutual Funds including account registration, subscription, redemption, and portfolios. Using Redis to store a list of mutual fund product data.
- Developing a REST API for the Forex Saving feature which includes account registration, buying, and selling.
 Developing REST API limit features for each Forex transaction and maintaining limit data. Used Redis to store current Dollar Exchange data, for each transaction calculation.
- Using Kafka for every transaction notification sent.
- Implement Liquibase for schema tables in the database and record any changes to the table schema.
- Tech stack: Java 17, Spring Boot, Oracle database, Redis, Kafka, JUnit, Liquibase.

PT Dua Delapan Resources / Mining company engaged in nickel ore exploration *Java Developer*

Jakarta, Indonesia Sep 2022 – Feb 2023

Developing a human resources information system

- Maintaining a mining materials trade shipping information application
- Developing a website-based IT Inventory application that is used to record the input process of goods entering or leaving the mining area (Pusat Logistik Berikat)
- Tech stack: Java 8, Spring Boot, PostgreSQL, Thymeleaf, JavaScript, JUnit

Maybank / Malaysian universal bank

Jakarta, Indonesia

Part-time Java Developer

Feb 2022 - Des 2022

- Develop web-based applications for Maybank customer loans
- Create an API application to handle the Eligibility Criteria, Credit Criteria, and Actual Conditions features
 of customers in the money lending business
- Tech stack: Java 11, Spring Boot, Oracle database, JUnit

Kimia Farma / Pharmaceutical company with the largest network of pharmacies

Jakarta, Indonesia

& health service providers in Indonesia

Big Data Analyst Intern

Aug 2022 – Sep 2022

- Create a data mart for sales, goods and customers. Successfully created a Sales Dashboard showing sales data for the Salicyl brand from January to June 2022
- Tech stack: Google Data Studio, Spreadsheet

Investree / B2B marketplace lending platform for SMEs *Back End Developer Intern*

Jakarta, Indonesia Jun 2022 – Jul 2022

 Finishing various tasks related to Backend Developer activities from Investree, such as Java OOP concepts, SQL databases, Spring Boot framework, and the final project of building a REST API for peer to peer lending with Spring Boot, Spring Security, PostgreSQL database

Tech stack: Java 8, Spring Boot, PostgreSQL

PT Bhimasena Research and Technology / Focuses on research and development of equipment in the military field

Bandung, Indonesia

Electronic and Software Engineer

Jun 2018 - May 2022

- Successfully designed a 25 kg capacity load cell sensor to measure UAV propulsion engines with a tolerance of 0.3-0.5%
- Able to design and create GUI software to control and monitor the measurement process of UAV propulsion engines in real time
- Successfully made the sensor data logging process and saved the measurement results of the UAV propulsion engine in the form of a CSV/Excel file
- Tech stack: C++, Qt framework, Arduino microcontroller

Education

Institut Teknologi Sepuluh Nopember (ITS)

Surabaya, Indonesia

Bachelor in Electrical Engineering

Aug 2016 - Mar 2020

• Final Project: Design Propulsion Sensor System and GUI Software on the test bench of the Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV)

Organization

Laboratorium Cyber Physical Otomasi dan Robot Industri

Surabaya, Indonesia

Laboratory Assistant

May 2017 - Sep 2019

 Accompanying students when carrying out practicums and compiling modules for programming language practicums. Creating modules for microcontroller training and Programmable Logic Controllers for high school students

Volunteering & Skills

- Volunteering: Industrial Automation Robotics ITS 2017 & 2018 (Coordinator Programmable Logic Controller), Siemens Science Technology 2017 (Instructor Workshop PLC)s
- Technical skills: Java, Spring Boot, Python, C++, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Oracle database